md.com 2018-11-30

# Privacy Policy | MD.com

This Privacy Policy describes how MD.com collects information from you, when you visit our website or use our mobile applications, respond to emails, sign up for notifications, or visit any page that displays our content or advertisements.

MD Health Solutions, Inc. ("MD.com," "We," "Us" or "Our") is committed to respecting the privacy rights of our customers, visitors, and users of its website ("You," "Your" and "Yourself") at www.md.com (the "Site") and related websites, applications, services and mobile applications provided by MD.com (collectively, the " **Services** "). This Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy”) explains how we collect information about You and how such information may be used. We also would like to explain what choices You have in managing Your privacy.

As with any site that You visit on the Internet, when You visit MD.com, we have the ability to collect information about You. Please read this Privacy Policy to understand how we collect information and what we do with the information we collect. Your use of this Site will be deemed conclusively to constitute Your acceptance of and agreement to the terms contained in this Privacy Policy.

## How MD.com Collects Information

We automatically track and collect the following categories of information when you visit our Site or use the Services, such as: (1) information about your IP Address, Mobile Device, and Browser; (2) the types of computers accessing the Site; (3) referring source which may have sent You to the Site; and (4) other information associated with the interaction of Your browser and the Site. Additionally, MD.com may collect information when you download and install certain applications and software we make available directly or through third-party providers. If you download our mobile application or use a location-enabled browser, we may receive information about your location and mobile device. If you access or use any telemedicine services on the Site, through [https://anywhere.md.com](https://anywhere.md.com/), or mobile applications provided by MD.com, please note that those services are governed and subject to additional terms and conditions and privacy policies. See **[Use of Telemedicine Platform or Application](https://www.md.com/privacy#use_of_telemedicine_platform_or_application)**

## Personal Information MD.com Collects

To use our Services, we may require You to provide us with certain information that personally identifies You (“Personal Information”). MD.com may ask You for Personal Information when You sign up for an account, complete optional survey forms, fill out optional contact forms for additional information on particular products and services or use a particular service. You can determine, to a large extent, what Personal Information You wish to submit on a voluntary basis to MD.com.

Personal Information may include: (1) contact data (such as Your e-mail address, phone number and Site password); and (2) demographic data (such as Your gender, Your date of birth and Your zip code). Additionally, portions of our Site may allow you to store Your healthcare providers, insurance information, and certain personal health information. If You communicate with us by, for example, e-mail or letter or SMS Text, any information provided in such communication may be collected as Personal Information.

## Why MD.com Asks for Your Personal Information

We regularly make improvements to our Services to provide You with a more personalized and useful experience. Collection of Personal Information also assists MD.com by allowing it and its affiliates to advertise its products and/or services in a more efficient manner. Through the use of Cookies and online data entry, survey, product purchase and registration forms, MD.com may monitor, in aggregate and individual form, Personal Information. Although Our primary goal in collecting Personal Information is to deliver a customized and personalized service to the users of the Services, We may also use Personal Information to: (i) send users e-mail notification of new features or information available through the Site or that MD.com otherwise feels might be of interest to users of the Services; and (ii) allow third party advertisers and retailers, and their affiliates, offering goods or services that MD.com thinks might be of interest to users to deliver relevant information and offers to users. We also collect IP addresses for systems administration and troubleshooting purposes and to report aggregate information to Our advertisers and others.

## HIPAA

We are not a "covered entity" under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, and the regulations promulgated thereunder, in effect or as amended (collectively known and referred to as "HIPAA"). Although We are not covered by HIPAA, We are committed to user privacy and have in place strict data security policies and measures, and ensure that users control access to their information.

On occasion, MD.com may act as a "Business Associate" of one or more Covered Entities (e.g., Healthcare Providers, such as doctors, hospitals or health plans) as defined by HIPAA. In those instances, to the extent required by law, MD.com will comply with the obligations imposed upon Business Associates and abide by the privacy policies of the Covered Entities.

## Your Account Registration

You must provide a valid email address in order to sign up for an account through the Services. In addition, you may provide us with your (1) full name, (2) phone number, (3) address, and (4) insurance data (such as insurance carrier and insurance plan). When you sign up for an MD.com account, we opt you in to receive emails from MD.com by default. You can manage your email preferences and modify some of the information associated with your account. Note that you cannot opt out of receiving required administrative or legal notices. If you feel that an unauthorized account has been created depicting you or your likeness, you can request its removal by sending email to [privacy@md.com](mailto:privacy@md.com). 

## Collection of Cookies and Use of Web Beacons

To enhance Your online experience, We may use small computer files that are transferred to Your computer's hard drive that contain information such as user ID, user preferences, lists of pages visited and activities conducted while browsing the Site (“Cookies”). Cookies do not contain personally identifiable information; however, once You choose to furnish a site with personally identifiable information, this information may be linked to the data stored in the cookie.

We use Cookies to understand site and Internet usage and to improve or customize the content, offerings or advertisements on our sites. For example, we may use cookies to personalize Your experience at our sites (e.g., to recognize You by name when you return to a site), save Your password in password-protected areas, and enable You to use shopping carts on our sites. We also may use cookies to help us offer You products, programs, or services that may be of interest to You and to deliver relevant advertising.

In limited circumstances we also may use tiny graphic image files imbedded in a web page or email that provide a presence on the web page or email and send back to its home server information from the user’s browser (“Web Beacons”) to collect anonymous, non-personal information about Your use of our Services and the sites of selected sponsors and advertisers, and your use of emails, special promotions or newsletters we send to you. The information collected by Web Beacons allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using the Services and selected sponsors' and advertisers' sites, or opening our emails, and for what purposes.

## Our Use of Website Analytics

We may use third party website analytics services in connection with the services provided on our Site. For example, we may record mouse clicks, mouse movements, scrolling activity, as well as any text that You type into the Site. These website analytics services do not collect Personal Information that You do not voluntarily enter into the Site. We use the information collected from these services to find usability problems to make the Services easier to use. The recordings will never identify You or Your account; they only record anonymous user information.

## Google Analytics Cookies Usage & Remarketing

We use Google Analytics first-party “cookies” and the DoubleClick third-party “cookie” for reporting and advertising. These first-party and third-party cookies are used together to help us better understand site user interests and online behavior in an aggregate and anonymous form. The Google Analytics first-party “cookies” are used to compile statistical information and reports on aggregate visitor activity on our website.

We use third-party cookies to enable Google Analytics demographics and interest reporting, which allows us to understand, in aggregate, the age, gender, and interests of our visitors.

In addition we may also use first-party and third-party Google Analytics and DoubleClick “cookies” for remarketing purposes. Remarketing allows our ads to be delivered to visitors on other third-party websites within Google's Display Network after they leave our website.

This system provides advertising that directly relates to offers that may be of interest to you based on your prior website visit(s). We gather this information from third parties through Google's Display Network. None of the data we collect from first and third party “cookies” can be linked to an individual person nor is this data able to personally identify any visitor to our website.

Additionally, Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. In summary, your anonymity is safe. If you wish to opt out of Google Analytics or Remarketing with Google Analytics, you can download the [Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) and follow the instructions provided or you can change your [ad settings here](http://www.google.com/settings/ads) and opt out of DoubleClick Remarketing Pixels.

If you want to permanently opt out of the DoubleClick cookie, you can install the [DoubleClick opt out extension](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin). You may also delete cookies from your internet browser by following your browser’s instructions.

## It’s Your Choice to Provide Personal Information

You may always choose not to provide us with any Personal Information. If you do not provide Personal Information, you can still access and use some of the MD.com services; however you will not be able to access and use certain key features of the Site Services that require your Personal Information.

## What other choices do you have?

Most computer systems and browsers offer their own privacy settings. We encourage you to use them to enhance your choices. Most browsers’ advanced settings allow you to disable cookies. However, if you do so, some site features and services may not work. Also, you must remember to manage your cookie settings for each computer and browser you use to access the Internet.

## Information Provided on Behalf of Children

MD.com does not collect information from children under the age of 13 in accordance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”) as discussed below. If you are a parent or legal guardian of a minor child, you may, use our Site on behalf of such minor child. Any information that you provide us while using the services on our Site on behalf of your minor child will be treated as Personal Information as otherwise provided herein.

## Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act

COPPA severely restricts what information can be collected from children under the age of 13. For this reason, children under the age of 13 in the United States are prohibited from using the Site and our services. The Site and our services are not directed at children, and MD.com does not knowingly collect any information from individuals under the age of 13. If we learn that we have received any information from an individual under the age of 13, we will use that information only to respond directly to that child (or a parent or legal guardian) to inform him or her that he or she cannot use the Site services and subsequently we will delete that information from our own servers.

## Keeping Information Confidential and Secure

Except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy, we will keep your Personal Information private and will not share it with third parties, unless we believe in good faith that disclosure of your Personal Information or any other information we collect about you is necessary to: (1) comply with a court order or other legal process; (2) protect the rights, property or safety of MD Health Solutions, Inc. or another party; (3) enforce our Terms of Use; or (4) respond to claims that any posting or other content violates the rights of third-parties.

The security of your Personal Information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the Personal Information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. For example, when you enter sensitive information on our Site, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (“SSL”).

Although we make good faith efforts to store Personal Information in a secure operating environment that is not open to the public, you should understand that there is no such thing as complete security, and we do not guarantee that there will be no unintended disclosures of your Personal Information. If we become aware that your Personal Information has been disclosed in a manner not in accordance with this Privacy Policy, we will use reasonable efforts to notify you of the nature and extent of the disclosure (to the extent we know that information) as soon as reasonably possible and as permitted by law.

## You May Change or Delete Your Information

As a registered User of MD.com, you can modify some of the Personal Information you have included in your profile or change your username by logging in and accessing your account. Upon your request, We will use commercially reasonable efforts to delete your account and the Personal Information in your profile; however, it may be impossible to remove your account without some residual information being retained by MD.com.

When you delete your account, you understand that removed certain content may persist in backup copies for a reasonable period of time (but will not be available to others). Furthermore, to the extent Personal Information about you has been shared with others, or other Users have independently uploaded and/or retained information about you, such information may also remain. Registered users who wish to close their account should request removal by sending email to [optout@md.com](https://www.md.com/contact/mailing-list-opt-out).

## Use of Telemedicine Platform or Application

Please note that all Telemedicine products and services accessible through MD.com are maintained by a third-party provider KB Medical Systems, LLC operating as CareClix. If you choose to use the Telemedicine Platform through https://anywhere.md.com or the MD.com Telemedicine mobile application for iOS and Android, please note that your Personal Information, identifiable health information (also known as Protected Health Information “PHI”) are subject to and governed by the following polices:

Telemedicine Terms & Conditions: <https://anywhere.careclix.com/terms-and-conditions>

Telemedicine Privacy Policy: <https://anywhere.careclix.com/privacy-policy>

## We Welcome Your Questions or Comments

MD.com welcomes Your questions and comments about our Privacy Policy or the use of Your Personal Information. Please send any questions or comments to MD.com to [privacy@md.com](mailto:privacy@md.com). 

Effective Date: June 14, 2017
